<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lorem on Hugo Foundation6</title>
    <link>https://example.org/categories/lorem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lorem on Hugo Foundation6</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 11:27:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.org/categories/lorem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lambentem constabat quinos quaeritis colorem amorem</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2016/11/lambentem-constabat-quinos-quaeritis-colorem-amorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 11:27:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2016/11/lambentem-constabat-quinos-quaeritis-colorem-amorem/</guid>
      <description>Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante. Donec eu libero sit amet quam egestas semper. Aenean ultricies mi vitae est. Mauris placerat eleifend leo. Quisque sit amet est et sapien ullamcorper pharetra. Vestibulum erat wisi, condimentum sed, commodo vitae, ornare sit amet, wisi. Aenean fermentum, elit eget tincidunt condimentum, eros ipsum rutrum orci, sagittis tempus lacus enim ac dui.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo is for lovers</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2015/08/hugo-is-for-lovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2015/08/hugo-is-for-lovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Goto hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your os and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at installing hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>